<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
	<properties>
		<title>About Quality-Check</title>
		<author>André Rouél</author>
		<author>Dominik Seichter</author>
	</properties>
	<body>

		<section name="What is Quality-Check?">
			<p>
				The goal of <em>Quality-Check</em> is to provide a small Java library for basic runtime code quality checks. It provides similar
				features to
				<code>org.springframework.util.Assert</code> <a href="http://static.springsource.org/spring/docs/3.1.x/javadoc-api/org/springframework/util/Assert.html">[1]</a>
				or
				<code>com.google.common.base.Preconditions</code> <a href="http://docs.guava-libraries.googlecode.com/git/javadoc/com/google/common/base/Preconditions.html">[2]</a>
				without the need to include big libraries or frameworks such as Spring or Guava. The package <em>Quality-Check</em> aims to
				replace these libraries and provide all the basic code quality checks you need. (If you are familiar with those classes, just look at our
				<a href="comparison.html">comparison</a> page.)
			</p>
			<p>
				The checks provided here are typically used to validate method parameters and detect errors during runtime. To
				detect
				errors before runtime we use JSR-305 Annotations. With these annotations you are able to detect possible bugs
				earlier. For more information look at FindBugs™ JSR-305 support.
			</p>
			<p>
				We consider our module as particularly suitable for APIs, which contain their own domain objects and services that are validated 
				using <em>Quality-Check</em> not only functionally, but also technically. Moreover, we provide an easy to use fail-fast description of an API 
				to immediately report at its interface any failure or condition that is likely to lead to failure.
			</p>
			<p>
				We noticed that many projects just copy
				<code>org.springframework.util.Assert</code> or <code>com.google.common.base.Preconditions</code>
				to get access to these quality checks. Therefore we provide these features and a small library that can be included in
				any application without big overhead.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section name="Why is it called check and not assertion?">
			<p>We think that checks of method arguments are not only assertion tests it's more over a condition to work properly.
				Beyond this, it supports you in writing faster contracts for your methods and classes. If nothing of this package makes
				sense please take a look at the concept
				<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_by_contract"><em>design by contract</em></a>.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section name="Example">
			<source><![CDATA[
/**
 * Sets the given object if it is not null.
 *
 * @throws IllegalArgumentException
 *         if the given argument is {@code null}
 */
setObject(final Object object) {
	if (object != null) {
		throw new IllegalArgumentException("Argument 'object' must not be null.");
	}
	this.object = object;
}]]></source>
			<p>
				can be replaces by:
			</p>
			<source><![CDATA[
/**
 * Sets the given object if it is not null.
 */
@ArgumentsChecked
setObject(final Object object) {
	this.object = Check.notNull(object);
}]]></source>
		</section>
		<section name="Why use Quality-Checks for your method parameters?">
			<p>
				<em>Quality-Check</em> brings several advantages to your project. If used extensively throughout your codebase, you will benefit from the
				following points. We will outline each one in a short paragraph below.
			</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Prevent technical errors due to invalid input parameters</li>
				<li>Detect errors early, where they occur</li>
				<li>Do not waste time by writing useless test to cover error detection branches</li>
				<li>No need to document exceptions thrown because of invalid method arguments</li>
			</ul>
			<subsection name="Prevent errors">
				<p>
					<em>Quality-Checks</em> to check the input arguments of a method, such as
					<code>Check.isNull(object)</code>
					or
					<code>Check.positionIndex(4, myList.size())</code>
					should be applied to every argument of every public method in your class, service or component. Why is that?
					If you
					check all arguments as soon as they are passed to your code, you do not need to deal with invalid argument
					values
					through the rest of your component or class. For example, if every public method ensures that no
					<code>null</code>
					values
					are passed to the class, you do not have to care about
					<code>null</code>
					values in your private methods.
				</p>
				<p>
					Therefore, <em>Quality-Checks</em> assist you in preventing
					<b>technical</b>
					errors in your classes, because they only have to work with valid arguments.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Detect errors early">
				<p>
					Often, in Java development, you have to deal with
					<code>NullPointerExceptions</code>
					or other faults which can be tracked back to invalid values
					passed to methods and handed further down until they
					crash in your code. Sometimes, it is hard to trace down where the
					invalid value came from.
					To identify invalid values
					as soon as possible and detect errors where they occur, we suggest to guard every public
					method with <em>Quality-Checks</em>.
				</p>
				<p>
					Using quality checks, erroneous input arguments are identified, as soon as they are passed to your component.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Avoid useless tests">
				<p>
					If you add checks for method arguments manually, you will notice that you have to write additional tests using
					invalid method arguments to cover
					these branches. One example for a manual check is here:
				</p>
				<source><![CDATA[
void doSomething(final List<String> list) {
	if( list == null ) {
		throw new IllegalArgumentException("Argument 'list' must not be null.");
	}
	if( list.isEmpty() ) {
		throw new IllegalArgumentException("Argument 'list' must not be empty.");
	}
}]]></source>
				<p>
					In this example, you would have to write two additional tests (one with a null list and one with an empty list),
					only to test these two branches. Alternatively, if you do not, your branch coverage will go down.
				</p>
				<p>
					<em>Quality-Checks</em> will save you from doing so! As calls to
					<code>Check.*</code>
					are method calls you will cover them in any test automatically. We make sure
					that <em>Quality-Check</em> works, so that you
					do not have to test it. See the example below:
				</p>
				<source><![CDATA[
@ArgumentsChecked
void doSomething(final List<String> list) {
   	Check.isNull(list, "list");
	Check.isEmpty(list, "list");
}]]></source>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="No need to write documentation for technical error cases">
				<p>
					Similar to the example of the branch coverage, you also write a lot of JavaDoc documentation for exceptions
					thrown in your
					methods, which check for illegal input parameters.
				</p>
				<source><![CDATA[
/**
 * Method does something.
 *
 * @throws IllegalArgumentException if list is null.
 * @throws AnotherIllegalArgumentException if list is empty.
 */
void doSomething(final List<String> list) {
	if( list == null ) {
		throw new IllegalArgumentException("Argument 'list' must not be null.");
	}
	if( list.isEmpty() ) {
		throw new AnotherIllegalArgumentException("Argument 'list' must not be empty.");
	}
}]]></source>
				<p>
					As quality check throws the exceptions and your code does not, there is no need for you to document these
					exceptions. You can focus
					on the really important documentation of exceptions which might be thrown by business logic.
					To show the caller of the
					method that
					quality-checks are in place and certain exceptions might be thrown, we add an
					<code>@ArgumentsChecked</code>
					annotation.
				</p>
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section name="Overview over the Quality-Check way">
			<div class="section">
			    <a href="./images/the_quality_check_way.png">
   					<img src="./images/the_quality_check_way_small.png" alt="Visualization of the Quality-Check way" />
   				</a>
			</div>
		</section>

	</body>
</document>
